CHAITANYA KAPOOR

chaitanya.7.kapoor@gmail.com

github.com/ckapoor7

□ ckapoor7.github.io

(Nationality: Citizen of the United States of America)

Research Interests

My research interests lie at the intersection of Deep Learning and Neuroscience, aiming to understand and reverse engineer neural computation. I aim to develop computational models of such neural circuits, with an overarching goal of designing efficient, biologically-constrained learning algorithms.

Education

University of California, San Diego

Aug. 2024 - Present La Jolla, CA

Post-Baccalaureate Student (NeuroML Group)

Advisor: Meenakshi Khosla

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Visiting Student (Senseable Intelligence Group)

Thesis: LUMIN: Light-sheet Microscopy Analysis Unified with Distributed and Domain-Randomized

Generative Models

Advisor: Satrajit Ghosh

Birla Institute of Technology and Science, Pilani

B.E. (Hons.) in Electrical and Electronics engineering

Nov. 2020 - July 2024

Jan. 2024 - July 2024

Pilani, India

Cambridge, MA

Honors & Awards

04/24NeuroMatch Academy: Computational Neuroscience Summer School

02/24COSYNE 2024: Undergraduate Travel Grant Award

04/23OxML 2023: ML × Health Summer School, Oxford Mathematical Institute

Publications

Multiplexed Expansion Revealing for Imaging Multiprotein Nanostructures in Healthy and **Diseased Brain**

J. Kang, M. Schroeder, Y. Lee, C. Kapoor, E. Yu, T. B. Tarr, K. Titterton, M. Zeng, D. Park, E. Niederst, D. Wei, E. S. Boyden

[Under review - Nature Communications]

RnR-ExM: Robust Non-Rigid Registration Challenge for Expansion Microscopy Volumes E. Besier, R. Zhang, Y. Bando, Y. Quéméner, C. Kapoor, M. Alawi, M. Hoffman, A. Dalca, A. Casamitjana, I. Arganda-Carreras, E. S. Boyden, H. Pfister, D. Wei

IEEE International Symposium on Biomedical Imaging (IEEE ISBI), 2023 - website

Attention-enabled Deep Neural Network for Enhancing UAV-Captured Pavement Imagery in Poor Visibility

C. Kapoor, A. Warrier, M. Singh, P. Narang, H. Puppala, R. Srinivas, A. P. Singh IEEE Multimedia Information Processing and Retrieval (IEEE MIPR), 2023 - paper

Fast and Lightweight UAV-based Road Image Enhancement Under Multiple Low-Visibility Conditions

C. Kapoor, A. Warrier, M. Singh, P. Narang, H. Puppala, R. Srinivas, A. P. Singh PerCom Workshops (PerSASN 2023) - paper

Dense Residual Networks for Gaze Mapping on Indian Roads

C. Kapoor, K. Kumar, S. Vishnoi, S. Ramanathan preprint

Research Experience

NeuroML Lab Aug. 2024 – Present

Supervisor: Prof. Meenakshi Khosla

La Jolla, CA

• Working on developing methods to quantify representational similarity in artificial and biological neural networks.

Talmo Lab May 2023 – Present

Supervisor: Dr. Talmo Pereira

Salk Institute, La Jolla, CA

- Working on the development of methods for pose estimation and tracking to quantify animal behavior through robust tracking of anatomical landmarks in 3D.
- Designing algorithms utilizing projective geometry to create inputs for a CNN that leverages geometric reasoning.

Senseable Intelligence Group

Jan. 2024 - July 2024

Supervisor: Prof. Satrajit Ghosh

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, MA

- Developed a distributed framework for large-scale (\sim 1TiB) image segmentation for light-sheet microscopy images.
- Designed a domain-randomized generative model, using spherical harmonics to synthesize cortical sections of ex-vivo human brains to enable zero-shot segmentation.
- Worked on designing few-shot, spatially guided semantic segmentation algorithms for MRI segmentation.
- Proposed the use of a topologically aware Graph Neural Network which is capable of encoding spatial and anatomical constraints.

Synthetic Neurobiology Group

Feb. 2022 - Jan. 2024

Supervisors: Prof. Ed Boyden, Prof. Donglai Wei

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, MA

- Worked on the development of a *generalist* 3D segmentation model for Expansion Microscopy (ExM) volumes for various animal species.
- Proposed a human-in-the-loop feedback learning mechanism, built on top of an existing deep learning framework, NucMM.
- Worked on developing a new joint-intensity and point-based, high throughput image registration algorithms having nanoscale precision (10-40 nm) for Multiplexed Expansion Revealing (multiExR). This work is currently under review at Nature Communications.

Camera Culture Group

August 2022 – Dec. 2023

Supervisor: Dr. Ramesh Raskar

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, MA

- Worked on extracting environments from surfaces of glossy objects from sparse, and unstructured views.
- Explored methods that incorporate shape priors, which enable us to turn everyday objects having unknown geometry into radiance-field camera to image the world from an objects perspective.

Invited Talks and Tutorials

02/24 Automating behavior quantification using deep learning, COSYNE 2024

06/23 SIS Symposium, Harvard SEAS, Seeing Beyond the Camera

Teaching Experience

Department of Mathematics, BITS Pilani

August 2023 - Dec. 2023

Teaching Assistant

Pilani, India

• Undergraduate TA: assisted with the course Combinatorial Mathematics (MATH F421)

Technical Skills

 $\textbf{Languages: Python, C, MATLAB, Unix Shell Scripting , $\underline{\text{PATE}}$X}$

Technologies/Frameworks: Keras, Tensorflow, Numpy, PyTorch, Git, OpenCV